Pierre Vautherin

Software Engineer Javascript

I am a big fan of React-redux and AWS solutions. I worked a few years in the publishing industry, before working in web development. I am a hard worker, motivated by technical challenges

p.vautherin@hotmail.com github.com/PierreVaut linkedin.com/in/pierrevautherin



Experience

SeLoger - Frontend developer

Oct 2020 - present

> Created and maintained webservices for Cloud clients

Photobox - Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Oct 2020

Al-in-Editor Team

- > Improved Conversion rate by implementing AI features (Autofill, Shuffle layout, Easy-Create)
- > Improved Time-to-action using frontend image compression
- > Improved UX using Cross-device Firebase dynamic link

Groupeer Technologies - Fullstack developer

Feb - July 2018

> Created a fleet management service for IoT devices

Project manager

2008 - 2017

Education

IFOCOP - 2018 - Full stack Javascript Training

- > frontend project: Fallout-style RPG in React
- > fullstack project: Realtime Bitcoin trading simulator

Sorbonne University - 2008 - Master's degree in Communication

∰ Miscellaneous

Native speaker French, fluent in English.

Passionate traveller and rider. Fond of trail running.

I really love cinema, especially Kubrick, Visconti and Tarkovsky.

Languages

Javascript ES6+ HTML CSS

Libs & Frameworks

React

Hooks

Redux-saga

Ramda

Backend

Node.js
Rest, GraphQL
PostgreSQL
MongoDB,
DynamoDB

Devops

AWS Lambda, EKS CircleCI

Versionning

Git

Project

Scrum & Kanban JIRA, Confluence Github